使用ChatGPT的另一个有趣的方法是用它写音乐。
Another fun way you can use ChatGPT is to write music with it.
我的意思是，如果你能写博客、文章或报告，以及无聊的，你知道的，工作报告或其他什么，商业案例，也许你可以写一些有趣的东西，比如写一些音乐，对吧？
I mean, if you can write blog posts or articles or reports and boring, you know, reports for work or whatever, business cases, maybe you can write something fun like write some music, right?
所以，至少，再一次，你将成为你自己的创造性自我，但我们将使用ChatGPT来看看我们是否可以在这里开始，让创意源源不断。
So at least, and again, you're going to be your own creative self, but we're going to use ChatGPT to see if we can kind of get it started here, get the creative juices flowing.
所以我不是以写歌为生，我这辈子从来没有写过一首歌。
So I don't write songs for a living, never written a song in my life.
事实上，我也从未使用过GPT，但我们现在就要做了。
In fact, I've never used GPT for this either, but we're going to do it right now.
我们将生活在边缘，看看这里的情况如何。
And we're going to live on the edge and see how it goes here.
所以我要进入我的聊天GPT。
So I'm going to go into my chat GPT.
我要说的是，我会表现得很好，因为我以前从未这样做过。
And I'm going to say, I'm going to be real nice because I've never done this before.
请给我写一首歌。
Please write a song for me.
我希望这首歌是关于什么的？
And what do I want the song to be about?
比方说这是一首儿歌。
Let's say it's a children's song.
所以我们要把它变成一首有趣的儿歌，对吧？
So we're going to make it a fun little children's song, right?
这是关于一只逃跑的猫，让我们看看是哪只猫，它迷路了，但找到了回家的路。
And it's about a cat who runs, let's see who cat, who gets lost but finds his way home to his mother.
最后，好吧，这就像披头士乐队的东西，这就像甲壳虫乐队的滚石乐队，泰勒·斯威夫特，不管你最喜欢的艺术家是谁，请给我写一首儿歌，这将是一首儿曲，这是关于猫迷路了，最后找到了他妈妈的路，所以我所做的就是，这将给我写首歌，让我们看看它能做什么这是我为你写的一首歌第一节
in the end all right this is this is like like beatle stuff here right this is like the Beatles rolling stones uh Taylor Swift whoever your favorite artist is please write a song for me children's song this is gonna be a children's song it's about cat gets lost and finds his way into his mother in the end so that's all i got right is this gonna write me a song let's see what it does clearly here's a song i've written for you what verse one
曾经有一只小猫，他喜欢在聊天中玩耍哦，可爱的，他整天在附近游荡，但有一天他瘦了下来，然后合唱对了哦，小猫，你不要迷路了，今天找回家的路，你妈妈在等她，她会很高兴她的小猫回来的，然后你做第一首诗，然后你合唱，还有另一首诗，你合唱对了
there once was a kitty cat he loved to play in chat oh lovely he roamed the neighborhood all day but one day he lost his weight and then the chorus right oh kitty kitty don't you stray find your way back home today your mommy is waiting she'll be glad to have her little kitty back and then you do the first verse and then you do a chorus and there's another verse then you do a chorus right
事实上，对于一首儿歌来说，还不错。
Not bad actually, for a children's song.
伙计，这是一首儿歌，对吧？
Man, this is a children's song, right?
所以，我不知道，这是出乎意料的好。
So this is, I don't know, surprisingly good.
因为它是从爸爸那里学来的，所以它不是抄袭。
And because it's pulling from dad and stuff, it's not plagiarism.
我不会再唱一首歌。
I'm not copying another song.
但我可以把它当作一首儿歌，这就是它的初衷，倒退。
But I could do this as a kids song and this is what it came with, backwards.
所以这是一首聪明、酷、好听的儿歌，对吧？
So that's kind of clever and cool, nice little kids song, right?
现在让我们说，你能让这个成为成年人吗？
So now let's say, can you make this an adult?
说唱歌曲好吧，所以我们将从孩子们转向说唱。我的意思是，我很好，我们在这里。我不确定这是否会改变太多。我本可以再生任何东西，但这肯定是一首成人说唱歌曲。哦，我们希望我不会在这里说任何语言。我是一只小猫。是的，这是我生活在狂野和自由的生活中。我日夜在这些街道上游荡，但有一天我失明了
rap song all right so we're gonna go from kids to rap i mean i'm pretty good we're we're out here i'm not sure if this is going to change much i could have regenerate whatever but certainly here's an adult rap song oh we're hopefully i won't be any language here i'm a kitty yeah that's me live in life wild and free i roam these streets all day and night but one day i lost my sight
哦，小猫，小猫，你今天不是迷路了吗？找到回家的路了吗？你妈妈在等她，她会很高兴她的小猫回来的。好吧，这太可怕了，所以首先我的写作很好，我的唱歌和说唱很糟糕，这是多么不酷
oh kitty kitty don't you stray find your way back home today your mama's waiting she'll be glad to have her little kitty back peace all right that was awful so first off my the writing's good my singing and rapping is awful and and how uncool is it to
像西装外套一样穿得很得体。
rap in like a suit coat.
不，但不管怎样，这将如何改变音乐？
No, but either way, how is this going to change music?
人们会写很多歌吗？真的，你知道，也许会努力让它变得更好？
Are people going to be able to write lots of songs and really, you know, maybe try to make this better?
但现在看起来很不错，对吧？
But right now that looked pretty good, right?
所以
So
再说一遍，如果你想写一首儿歌，让我们回到这里，回到我们的小猫身边。
Again, if you want to write, like, a little children's song, let's go back up here to our little kitty here.
也许你想为你的孩子写一首小的定制歌曲，让它对他们来说很特别。
And maybe you want to write a little custom song for your little child and make it special for them.
也许加上一些东西，比如小猫的名字就是你自己猫的名字。
Maybe add in things like the kitty cat's name is your own cat's name.
你知道，我们曾经养过一只猫，它的名字叫安格斯。
You know, we used to have a cat, his name was Angus.
所以也许不是说，曾经有一只小猫，有一只名叫安格斯的单侧小猫。
So maybe instead of says, there once was a kitty cat, there was a one-sided kitty cat named Angus.
这个故事是关于我们的猫安格斯的。
And the story is about Angus, our cat.
你知道，这对一个小孩子来说可能真的很聪明和酷，对吧？
You know, and that might be really clever and cool for a little kid, right?
那不是很有趣吗？
And wouldn't that be fun?
这是一个有趣的方式，你可以使用聊天GPT开始产生想法。
That's a fun way that you can use chat GPT to start generating ideas.
如果你让我写一首关于一只迷路或迷路的小猫的歌，我会花一整天的时间，一天又一天的时间，这太可怕了，这是一首更有节奏和正确的歌。
If you were to ask me like write a song about a kitty cat who lost his way or got lost, it would take me a full days, days and days that would be terrible, where this is something that's more rhythmical and right.
所以这是另一种有趣的娱乐方式。
So this is another interesting way for fun.
你可以玩聊天GPT，玩得很开心。
You can play around and have fun with chat GPT.